of the industry trends and development
that we've witnessed in the last few
months
post this our cfo which the gopal bala
chamberlain will share the financial
performance of the company for the
quarter and the year ended march 31 22.
the industry registered a
gdpa growth of 11.1 for fi 22.
as for public disclosures the combined
ratio of the industry was 119.2
for nine months fi 22 as compared to
110.4 percent for nine months fi 21
and the industry reported a loss of 4.05
billion rupees as against profit after
tax of 55.6 billion rupees for nine
months fi 22 21.
further the overall combined ratio for
the private multi-line general insurance
was 112
112 in nine months fi 22 as compared to
104.6 in nine months fi-21 2021.
the industry's solvency at nine months
fy 22 was worsened to
1.71 times as against 2.07 times at nine
months of fy 21.
so moving to the quarter under review
the industry delivered a mixed
performance as per the data published by
cm the new vehicle sales witnessed
stepping growth of private car segment
on the back of supply chain supply chain
challenges
the two-wheeler segment remained far
from recovery while the commercial
vehicle segment has shown growth
supported by underlying demand
health insurance on the other hand
contributed significantly to the overall
industry growth in line with the
expectation and is now the largest
contributing segment to the gdp of the
industry the commercial line witnessed
robust growth in sync with current
market environment
coming to the business impact for us the
community has grown it's grown
in line with the market growth of 12.7
percent this is excluding crops and
markets as against the lower growth that
we witnessed till nine months of fi-22
within the quarter the growth momentum
has increased each month and the company
has significantly outgrown the market in
the month of march 2022.
coming to the growth for key segments
during the quarter for motor the company
has grown faster than the industry and
we have now attained market leadership
in this segment
for the year
our investment in the retail health side
has started
to show results and has resulted in our
agency channel premium growth of 29.5
for the quarter
as indicated in our previous calls after
a thousand retail health agency managers
to be added to our employee base we have
now onboarded 750 of them during this
fiscal and the balance 250 offers have
been made
we expect the growth to accelerate and
accelerate in the next few quarters as
the sales force starts getting
productive
the corporate agency channel including
vanquishers is back in the black with
overall growth of nineteen point four
percent
within this ica bank distribution group
grew by twenty four point nine percent
primarily driven by health inability sme
and motor business
and other distribution partners acquired
through the integration grew fifteen
point nine percent during the same
period
our business source through our website
grew by twenty percent within this our
health business grew by twenty three
percent travel grew by hundred and
thirty percent and motor grew by 10
percent
business source through strategic
alliance partners in the digital
ecosystem grew by 98.2
overall our digital solutions has
enabled us to increase our digital
revenues by up to 7.74 billion for the
current year which accounts to accounts
to 4.3 percent of our overall gdp
as for the commercial lines are
concerned we experience robust growth
driven by 17.8 growth in the sme segment
let me now give you a update on some of
our other key initiatives
on the integration i'm very happy to
share that as we speak isis lombard
stands as the second largest non-life
insurer in india
exactly as envisioned while evaluating
the scheme as a potential transaction
the integration enabled us to strengthen
our market leadership augment and
further strengthen our diverse
distribution channels
the revenue and operating operational
synergies the thirty plans are on track
and gopal will talk about this in detail
in a segment
our ielts care app has surpassed 1.3
million downloads with successful
submission of
over one lakh thirty thousand claims and
over 70 000 teleconsultation requests
the recently added feature phase scan
helps users to keep a track of vitals
such as blood pressure heart rate
respiration rate etc all without any
additional devices and from the comfort
and safety of one's home
i'll take care is built to be user
friendly and a continuous engagement
platform which is increasing our ability
to cross sales
we are also pleased to share with you
that we are the first large insurer to
move our entire core systems onto the
cloud this year
in our data center we had about 110
applications across 600 servers and
around 1 000 terabyte of data
moving our complete setup onto cloud has
given us some immediate benefits
including stability
availability and scalability
as such some of the investments that we
have made during the year in
distribution and technology is bearing
fruit and we expect to see momentum in
growth as we head into the next
financial year
we intend to continue with our expansion
across distribution digital technology
and claim services towards this we have
planned additional investments in the
range of
rupees 1 billion to rupees 1.5 billion
during this year during the coming year
i will now request gopal to take you
through the financial numbers for the
recently concluded quarter
thanks bhagav and good evening to each
one of you i will now give you a brief
overview of the financial performance of
the company for quarter 4 and fy 20 2022
we have put up the results presentation
on our website you can access it as we
walk you through the performance numbers
the effects of the re-merging the
financials have been incorporated in the
form of opening network as on april 1
2021.
further the financials for the current
year represent numbers of the merged
entity and the comparative numbers for
the previous year in the financials
pertain to standalone ics and lombard
and hence are not comparable
the company has enhanced disclosure
requirement of reserving triangles by
giving separate reserving triangles for
motor third party
and non-motor third-party lines of
businesses
this is in accordance with the
regulatory guidelines on public
disclosures which is applicable to all
the players in the market
you may refer to slide number 29 and 30
of the industrial presentation on the
reserving triangle disclosures
our gross direct premium income of the
company was at rupees 179.77 billion in
effect with 2022 as against rupees
140.03 billion in fbi 2021 the industry
reported a double digit growth of 11.1
on a lower base for a similar period
our gdp growth was primarily driven by
growth in preferred segments given that
our approach has always been growing
business sustainably the fire segment
gdpi was replaced 27.5 billion in fi-22
as against rupees 21.58 billion in fbi
21.
as indicated in our results presentation
the overall gdp of our property and
casualty segment was rupees 50.24
billion in fbi 222 as against
39.29 billion in fbi 21.
on the retail side of business gdp of
the motor segment was at rs 82.8 billion
in fbi 22
as again should be 70.2 billion in fbi
to harness the potential of these
segments we have been expanding our
distribution network to increase
penetration entire three entire course
cities our agents which includes the
point of sale has increased to 88 539 as
on march 31 2022 from 81 969 as on
december 31 2021.
the advanced premium numbers was rupees
33.68 billion
as at march 31 2022 as against
34.59 billion as at 31st december 2021.
resultantly combined ratio was 108.8
percent in fy 22
as against 99.8 percent in fbi 21
and 111 percent in nine months fbi 2022
combined ratio was hundred and three
point two percent in quarter four five
twenty two as against hundred and one
point eight percent in quarter four fy
twenty one
and hundred and four point five percent
in quarter three five twenty two
our investment assets rose to rupees
three eighty seven point eight six
billion at mark 31 2022 from rupees
374.54 billion at december 31 2021.
our investment leverage net of
borrowings was 4.23 times at mars 31
compared to 4.23 times at december 31
2021.
investment income was at rs 30 billion
in fy 22 as against rupees 21.96 billion
in fbi 21. on a quarterly basis
investment income was would be seven
point zero six billion in quarter four
five twenty two as against rupees five
point three seven billion in quarter
four f by twenty one
our capital gains was at risk seven
point three eight billion in fi-22 has
against
rupees 3.59 billion in fbi 2021
capital gains for quarter 4 fy 22 was at
rs 1.36 billion as against rupees 0.66
billion in quarter four s by 21.
the successful integration of the
de-merged business of bartix into the
company
has led to optimization of our
organizational structure
rationalization of offices
efficiencies in claim settlement
practices and technology applications
this will result in an annualized
synergy benefits of rupees 2 billion
of which rupees 0.7 billion has been
realized in fy 2022.
our profit before tax was rupees 16.84
billion in fi 22 as against rupees 19.54
billion and fi 21
whereas pbt was rupees 4.1 billion in
quarter four fi 22 has again should pays
4.5 billion in quarter four f by 21.
as explained above the company has seen
higher growth momentum in q4
fy 22 and within that in the month of
march 2022
due to the current accounting norms this
results in a printing of sourcing costs
whereas the benefit of earned premium
will be realized over the policy period
consequently profit after tax was rupees
12.71 billion in fbi 22. as against
rupees 14.73 billion in fbi 21. whereas
profit after attack stood out to be 3.13
billion in q4 fi 22 as the game should
be 3.46 billion and q4f521
the board of directors of the company
has proposed a final dividend of rupees
5 per share for fi 2022. the payment is
however subject to approval of
shareholders in the ensuing and general
meeting of the company the overall
dividend for f522 including
the proposed final dividend is rupees
nine per share
written on average equity was fourteen
point seven percent in fy twenty two as
against twenty one point seven percent
in fy twenty one the return on equity
for q4 f5 22 was 14
as against 18.8 percent in q4 f by 21.
solvency ratio was at 2.46 times at mars
31 2022 as against 2.45 times at
december 31 2021 which continued to be
higher than the minimum regulatory
requirement of 1.5 times
as i conclude i would like to reiterate
that we continue to stay focused on
profitable growth
sustainable value creation and
safeguarding interest interest of policy
holders at all times
i would like to thank you all for
attending this earnings call and we will
be happy to take any specific questions
that you may have thank you
thank you very much we will now begin
the question and answer session
anyone who wishes to ask a question may
press star in one on their touchstone
telephone
if you wish to remove yourself from the
question queue you may press star into
participants are requested to use
handsets while asking a question
ladies and gentlemen we will wait for a
moment while the question q assembles
participants
you may press star in one to answer
questions
the first question is from the line of
shivani from clsa please go ahead
hi thank you for the opportunity so a
couple of questions i had i'll probably
just take two and then get back in the
queue uh first one is on the tp hike
rate uh that was announced and uh what
is the in what is your feedback on how
comfortable are you with the kind of
hike
uh that the regulator had proposed and
if you can help us get to an idea i mean
in spite of the hike i think given that
the car underlying car sales is still
weak if you can help us understand how
much proportion of your motor tt book is
private cars that would be the first
question second is on your uh
so just looking at your march 22 uh data
month the monthly data
so the uh uh the uh
the trend in your moto tp book was quite
strong and it was uh stronger than the
industry for that matter so if you can
give me uh so if you can help us
understand that and lastly on the loss
ratios for fire it's uh come down quite
dramatically in this quarter so if you
can help us understand that please any
questions
um thanks shivani um so let me uh
take the questions
give the answer the same sequence so if
you look at the uh
pp rate hike uh it's different across
different segments but the long term pp
rates hike is
uh is a bit higher overall at a
portfolio level for the industry if
weighted average increase comes to
roughly about three odd percent plus
minus
um
you know honestly speaking given the
general inflation that we see
we would have liked to see slightly
higher rates in certain categories in
certain certain categories we are fine
with the rate height that has been given
so in aggregate maybe a little bit
higher would have been
appropriate is our view on this
when is it expected as of now the
understanding is that it will come
around may
uh so that's where we are on the tp uh
hike
in terms of the mix i'll ask gopal to
answer the next point on the on the
private side
yeah so uh sure as you can see uh so far
as we we have given on this slide uh
this split of od and tp which is roughly
about 40.68 billion is zone damage and
about
42.12 billion is third party
within that 42.12 private car third
party will be about 13.49 billion
coming back to your question on on
growth i think what's happened as we've
been kind of uh
explaining for the last few quarters is
that
we took some calibrate call on
kind of
re-adjusting our portfolios away from
certain private car segments given the
pricing competition that we saw on the
private car and the website
and increasing uh
on the cv side again very calibrated
very selective calls
based on uh you know ground level
insights plus some experimentation that
we've been doing for the last three
years to
uh
to figure out if uh some of those books
are going to be uh you know better risk
for us
now when in retail when you cut down you
know the
the number goes away immediately but to
build up it takes some some time so
actually on the commercial side the
growth momentum has now picked up and
what we've been kind of uh indicating is
that if you look at our own portfolio
mix unlike the market where
out of the total motor book roughly 45
will be commercial vehicle for us that
was in the teens maybe you know 15 to 17
that as we've been saying that should go
to roughly in the mid-20s
uh so that journey has now started
we will have to see if we can maintain
the momentum of growth of march but
clearly the
the increase in the market share of cv
is something that we expect going ahead
and your last question on fire loss
ratios share again i think i think
that's one segment where we keep talking
about saying that uh
a quarterly loss ratio may not
necessarily be reflective of the
underlying
outcome of the performance the better
number to look at will be more i would
say
financial year numbers in fact within
that
i mean there could be years where
because of let's say various large
losses or catastrophic years in fact
the loss ratio of that particular this
segment could get impacted
so hence
quarterly numbers may not necessarily
kind of reflect as i said the underlying
outcome look at more the annual numbers
for the fire part of the business
okay thank you
thank you
the next question is from the line of
abhishek saraf from jefferies please go
ahead
uh yeah thanks for the opportunity so i
just had a few following questions from
the earlier question last so so you
mentioned that in the cv we are looking
at a higher
mix in the uh so what is giving us
confidence in terms of maintaining or
containing the loss ratios in that if
you can just give us a few more details
in the kind of experiments that you have
run and uh means where are we deriving
this confidence from uh secondly if you
can help me understand i believe that we
have taken uh hikes in motor od segment
so what would be the
average quantum of hike that we would
have taken and which kind of car segment
and
uh is it across the board that we have
taken in the new
or basically
in the sense that for new cars or is it
across the board for new and old cars i
have a few more questions after this
we'll uh just after if you can answer
this i'll follow up here yeah thanks
thank you so in terms of
uh i think we've been talking about what
we've uh the way we've handled this
again if you again reiterate the point
it is not as if we believe the whole tv
portfolio is
hardly turned uh viable or sustainable
or profitable
if you look at the overall industry mix
cv will be as i said between 45 to 50 we
are not talking about going anywhere
near that number now what we've been
doing for the last three years uh again
at various times we've talked about this
is that based on ground level insights
uh based on some changes that we are
seeing both at
in certain micro segments certain
markets
uh based on certain usage patterns or
accident patterns that are changing in
certain states or
even some amount of
you know the regulatory uh you know and
the compliance standards in some of
these markets
we uh have been identifying some
segments that we believe are viable
today than work with what they were in
the in the past
and what we've been doing as a company
is that we've been taking small bits to
see you know writing small amounts of
business uh reserving at a level where
we believe uh you know it is very very
conservative but allowing the team to
write some of those businesses to see
what is the
experience that we have over the next
two to three years some of those
experiments have proved to be in line
with our expectations so those are areas
where we are scaling up businesses
so so that's the confidence that we are
getting in terms of the the segments of
business now in terms of
and the approach that we are taking is
not just a loss ratio of you you're not
looking at loss ratio you look at the
combined ratio in terms of sourcing cost
and loss ratio together and wherever
there is more uh viability that's where
we are taking those calls
in terms of uh
you know
in terms of uh private car the
increases reasonably across board there
are one or two aims which haven't agreed
uh we are discussing but most of the
areas we've taken by synthesis
thanks for that answer
just if you can help us understand
you can share the
the quantum of hikes on an average that
we would have taken
it could be single regulation it's not
as if you've taken a huge hike it will
be a single digit
okay okay that's very helpful uh
secondly uh on
just notice that in the calamity losses
our share of losses have actually gone
up in this year
so
is it only because of integration with
bharti extra or is there more to it so
if you can help me understand the
rsh is our share of premium also have
gone up uh proportionately
in line with the losses as well
yeah so this was largely the cycle on
top that you're talking about if you
look at it
if you look at the last 10 12 cats our
share of losses being significantly
lower than our normal market share
uh in talk to we had two of our
corporate exposures that got hit so it
was kind of a you know unfortunate
concentrated event not uh as if there
was a large impact across board so
that's why we have a impact in the topic
because in in those cases here in the
western market where we have a slightly
higher share than our natural market
share so when you look at a you know
let's say lost share that you got
relative to the market here in these
markets they get lower
yeah thanks vargo that's very helpful
thanks a lot
thank you
the next question is from the line of
madhukar ladda from illara capital
please go ahead
hello
yeah uh
yeah thanks for for the opportunity
um so
you know your od loss ratios for uh odi
and tp and especially tp actually
uh for
q4 have risen quite materially and
if you look at
the quarter by quarter trend there is
quite a bit of volatility
now
uh you know when we look into the future
uh how should we be thinking about it
should we be thinking more in terms of
you know exit rate will be uh more
appropriate for next year
or the the the fuller rate as a base uh
and so what what sort of
how do you sort of project these things
or how do you look at it
so if you look at on the water own
damage segment
i think to my mind uh when you look at
more the exit rates for f
quarter four
is will be largely reflective of the
trend line that one would one could
potentially see so far as the way
forward is concerned and the reason why
we are saying is uh
in line with what we are discussed even
in our
earlier calls the thought process is to
try and see how we can get significantly
into
writing businesses which will be
relatively
uh driven in so far as more on
let's say high loss ratios and
relatively lower cost of sourcing late
businesses
that's the thought process that we have
in terms of increasingly building the
book and that's the reason why i would
say quarter 4 on the motor own damage is
largely reflective of what one could
experience at least in so far as
the trend line for the future is
concerned having said that obviously we
continue to kind of micro segment the
portfolio to see which are the
segments which we want to
select and underwrite in terms of
building the overall book but the
thought process is in line with as i
said
build a book which is relatively uh high
lr and low experience in so far as cost
of sourcing is concerned
on the third party portfolio i think uh
maybe i think what you could
the full year numbers are largely
representative of what one could
experience in so far as
the way forward is concerned quarter
four specifically i think
in line with what we had
done in quarter four of last year if you
recollect i think there were those
supreme court judgments which had come
through
this is which we had to kind of revisit
all the uh
outstanding cases that we had as of the
previous year and we had to kind of
strengthen the reserving requirements uh
assuming the fact that we could expect
an increase in average claim payout
consequent to those judgments on the
outstanding cases as well
on the similar lines i think what we
have experienced over the last couple of
years which is for understandable
reasons that
the courts in india which is
predominantly where you get bulk of the
motor third party orders being received
that has not been functioning at full
force uh while we have started to see
particularly maybe quarter four we have
already seen things coming back but at
least over the last i would say
three to six quarters
the courts have not necessarily been
functioning at full swing
what this does is obviously it kind of
starts to have an impact in so far as a
trend line of uh
settlements or cl or closures of cases
of third party that we would have done
relative to the historical past
which would mean obviously given the
fact that there has been some lag in so
far as the extent of closures that we
would have normally seen which could
happen in the future period we obviously
have to kind of factor in for or maybe
build in an element of uh
further inflation assumption as a part
of our reserving book
particularly the element of interest
that we will have to add in so far as
our reserve reserving circumstance and
hence
the trend line for q4 on the third party
book will be more representative of what
one could expect so far as future
trend line is concerned
uh
that's what i think for
q4 even for tp
is
for
yeah and the other i think one should
also be mindful is i think given the
fact that we also strengthened
the reserving uh book of uh
the motor third party pool as you would
have seen in terms of the enhanced
disclosures
this element of increased
interest which we or inflation that will
build in as a part of the reserve has
obviously led in so far as the
earthquake motor pool book is concerned
we have obviously strengthened the
reserve however on aggregate basis
we have motor third party which is
actually reflecting a small amount of
reserve releases
got it got it
um also then um
when we are selecting business
and the attempt is to bring the combined
uh more under control
not just look at the loss ratio
right
uh i'm i'm guessing the comparative
intensity is driving us
in this direction
um and and that's why they seem you know
slightly probably lower commission
ratios and uh and expense ratios in
focus would that be right to say and
what would be like the trend for uh fi
so more than the company of company
intensity is overall driving up the
overall combined for motor but if you
look at from a pure rv perspective
businesses which are high lr but low
expense tissue are better businesses
because the expense is upfront
lr comes over the period
right right
and our expectation on how uh you know
like the integration the party and what
should be uh our expense ratios and
you know what sort of expense ratios
should we expect in f520 to install like
any guidance on that
so introvert synergy number google has
explained so very difficult to put out a
numbers uh uh madhukar because i think
on the one side as we have put out what
is what will be the annualized energy
numbers which we put out as a part of
the opening remark
which is rough
sorry having said that i think what we
will continue to do when we look at
let's say fi 23 or maybe the year
thereafter we would want to continue to
kind of stay invested
in building some of our expansion plans
particularly what we have spoken about
on let's say on the health
agency distribution side we want to
continue to stay invested on building
our digital opportunities that we see
including the investments in technology
and claim service so to some extent i
think lastly what would end up is
obviously we would we are pretty much on
track in order to kind of realize the
benefits of synergy but at the same time
you would want to kind of use some of
these to kind of
increase the opportunity that we see on
account of the renewed growth momentum
that we have seen for ourselves
so if you if you remember what we had
discussed when we did the
transaction we had said that for a
couple of years our combined issue will
be elevated and then it will start
coming down
if you see our combined ratio for this
quarter it's
related to the last two quarters it's
already trending down
so that is an ongoing effort that we
will make to keep the combined ratio uh
under control now we've also said that
uh as a strategy rather than bringing
combined down to 100 and delivering a 20
rv we want to keep on investing and
grow the book for a bit faster
consequently the other we may have come
down to the high teams
but eventually on your improvement and
combined that that should continue
understood understood and final question
uh i was reading the notes to accounts
uh there is a 65 crore payment
of gst uh under protest and an
additional agreement to pay 40 crores
can you explain that uh and and you know
what is this the result of and
uh
yeah the implication which i mean
yeah so these are a couple of matters as
what we have put out
as a part of that disclosure on the
notes to accounts
as an insurance company we are entitled
to claim
input credit in so far as settlement of
motor claims related expenses are
concerned
both with respect to the arrangement
that we have either on a cash list or
whether on a reimbursement basis
uh in so far as the
gst department is concerned i think they
seem to kind of allege that possibly we
are not entitled to claim certain inputs
with respect to some of those
motor claim related
expenses so that's one
the second is
aspect is again with respect to
realization of as a part of claim
settlement again in the context of motor
portfolio we do kind of
end up
having certain element of salvages
the view of the department is that on
that particular amount of salvage
amount that we end up realizing there
should be an element of gst
applicability on on the extent of
realizations that we have made
we have consulted
the
expert opinions as well as senior
councils on this in terms of the stand
that the company has taken both with
respect to the eligibility of input
credit or motor claims
as well as whether there will be any
element of applicability of gst and so
far as salvage related
realizations are concerned the standard
of the company is pretty much uh
well found and uh we and it is legally
correct
uh so at this point of time obviously
that's the reason why the amount that of
65 crores is paid under protest and
another coffee cross is something that
we will uh we are committed to pay
at appropriate point of time in due
course we will be filing a refund for
getting this uh amounts back but at this
point of time these amounts are largely
kind of paid under protest
uh what we clearly understand is
obviously this is something which is
applicable more at an industry level and
hence to that extent collectively we
will the stand of the industry is
something that we will work with and
ensure that
we are able to get the rightful amount
that is due back to us
understood understood so this is an
industry phenomena so the tax department
is absolutely this is not specific to
isis
this both the issues are at an industry
level applicable to
almost all the players in the world
got it
thanks thanks that's very helpful
thank you very much a request to all the
participants please restrict to two
questions for participants if time
common please come back in the question
q for a follow-up question
the next question is from the line of
players chain from otila roswell
financial service please go ahead
good evening everyone uh firstly could
you talk about or the health claim
ratios
on the retail side in particular and
also the group health uh how have they
faired in q4
and uh
are they back to pre-covert levels or
there are certain elements which are
still there with respect to kovid and
how do you
see this going ahead i'll ask my second
question after that
so if you look at the split of
the health loss ratios which has been
given in the aggregate on the
presentation deck the breakup of that in
terms of
the employer employee portfolio or let's
say the corporate book that number for
quarter 3 was 93.1 that number for
quarter four is uh
95.3 percent
and on the retail indemnity book
uh the losses shows in quarter three was
about 65.7 and for quarter four that
number stands at about 57.6 percent
definitely has come up and so this is
more of a normalized level now and we
can presume it to be in a similar
trajectory going on right
so when you look at for example on the
corporate uh or let's say the employer
employee book we have always spoken
about saying that uh
typically particularly the large
corporates tends to kind of operate at a
loss ratio which could be ranging
anywhere between 95 to 100 anywhere
between that
and in so far as the relatively small
and mid corporate book is concerned they
generally tend to kind of operate on
again the employer employee part at
anywhere between 90 to 95 which is why
on a blended basis
i think one generally gets to see the
loss ratios which are relatively around
those 95 threshold however the cost of
acquisition with respect to these
businesses
particularly the large corporate tends
to be more direct and hence to that
extent on an aggregate basis on a
combined ratio book it
becomes viable for us to
underwrite having said that i think over
the last three or three quarters we have
been kind of talking through
particularly on the employer employee
book given the fact that we have seen
particularly this year the impact of
covet losses playing out
we have been affecting
clearly price increases
in so far as the renewal of the
portfolio is concerned while we had
indicated a price increase in the range
of 15 to 20 during our
quarter one earnings call but
subsequently as in when the actual
renewals have happened we have been able
to fight realizations which have been
slightly higher than that and
even with the increased price
realization we have been able to clearly
hold on to incur more than 90 percent of
the renewals in so far as the employer
employee or let's say the corporate book
is concerned
on the retail side again the thought
process is pretty much similar we
continue to keep looking at
the portfolio outcome in terms of what
is the desired loss ratio of the book
in general i think particularly the
indemnity book i mean depending on the
kind of book that you write the loss
ratios could range anywhere between i
would say 60 to 70 percent
on a steady state whereas the relative
cost of acquisition in the initial
periods would tend to be relatively
higher given the investments that we are
making on building distribution
so so that's that's what i would say in
so far as steady state
loss experiences are concerned both on
the corporate health or let's say the
retail indemnity book
so the second question is more broad
level and a slightly longer term as well
so if you look at you know the efforts
that uh you know uh players like you all
have taken with regards to
uh
tech enabled cleaning settlement
processes on the health side or on the
motor side there's several initiatives
that have been taken so do you see that
this
benefit the benefits of these efforts
will get more reflected in the pricing
coming down
uh or it would translate into more uh
combined ratio improvement uh so what
would be the strategy that i long will
be adopting in in order to you know uh
to take benefits of these measures
so in terms of our long-term thought
process uh
this is just what you're talking about
is definitely correct but it's only one
element of what we are
how we are building this
so if you look at
for example on our
claims um you know on the health side we
have launched that ai driven uh
authorization
you know the ml engine
for settling uh
settling plays for uh corporates that's
currently running at a shade lower than
we believe that number will keep
increasing as we go along but the
approach is across multiple levels so
uh if you if you think about it uh you
know the entire approach with i'll take
care was to look at uh an engagement and
con
you know a continuum of care approach
with corporates and we believe there are
multiple advantages of that beyond cost
sale upsell engagement renewals etc
even at the time of claims we believe in
the longer term we will see some
benefits so we are already beginning to
see that uh all you know more than 40
percent of our corporate client claims
are coming even reimbursement cases are
coming through that app
uh we are
what we've seen in the past is when we
had moved the entire claim service
in-house back in 2009
because we run the complete data and do
a lot of analytics around it we are able
to control uh we could at that point in
the control flows better on top of it we
built a lot of capability again using
artificial artificial intelligence to
identify surveillance claims better now
as we digitize the entire journey uh you
know the ability to run those engines
better becomes even uh you know you know
you have a ability to run those engines
even better so we are already beginning
to see some benefits in terms of solving
claims being managed better lastly we
believe if you can drive the video
consultation tele consultation uh you
know as a as a model to even control
unnecessary hospitalization that could
be additional benefit so
overall there is a you know a very
comprehensive thought process in terms
of using technology to
uh both give better convenience and
service to customers and in the process
into our
relative uh you know
lost costs for uh for the health claims
thanks thanks
thank you
the next question is from the line of
sanket gora
from sparta capital advisors please go
ahead
thank you for the opportunity uh
the price highs which we have taken in
motor od which we have said is largely
limited to the new business or we have
taken five bike in the windows premium
too and then this just wanted to check
whether it is just limited to cars
new private car some games
okay new private cars so so so
the control of price like we have taken
does this will will really help in
improving the loss ratios which which
are currently 68 in 22 and 73 in four
quarters so expected improvement in the
loss ratio because of this current price
size
uh we will have to see a few things you
know one of the things that we are
watching very closely usually
claim inflation because the input costs
are going up for everyone so there is a
risk that there won't be a claiming
session though till now in spite of the
inflation the team has managed it really
well uh in terms of controlling the
ac you know average claim size inflation
we are also you know driving a lot of
our non-oem source policies through our
vpn network that number has really gone
up this year so you know so we are
trying multiple strategies to prevent
that from going up but fact of the
matter is that we've seen significant
increase in input cost so there is a
risk that there would be an incision
because of that now if that happens then
we may not be able to see that uh you
know benefit
but
our sense is that at this point in time
where the private car only lost issues
are
it needs a price increase
if so factory whether whether we factor
in the equation or not so
uh so difficult to predict whether we
see improvement in loss ratio if the acs
inflation doesn't happen the answer is
yes but you would have to guard against
that
but is this a industry phenomena the
price that you are seeing across the
page will happen
the reason i'm asking is that is a
potential risk for our market share loss
if they are the only guys who have taken
prices
we don't think so because uh you know if
you see
the market share the recalibration that
we have to do we've effectively done
this year this is your only market share
this year has gone down largely for that
reason right because we felt that the
pricing was not
adequate uh where we are focusing on the
effort that we are building in terms of
our digital and agency channels uh you
know maybe some of the you know the uh
you know the slightly older segment we
remain reasonably confident about
holding onto a market share and uh
decide and something that we've been
saying that you know these two years
have been unusual because
you know people have benefited from
lockdowns and different times on the
motor portfolio right yeah and
traditionally whenever we see pricing
aggression it lasts for 12-18 months and
then things are you know correct back we
were talking about a pricing correction
requirement even before the
pandemic right
so market was
pandemic there was inaudible felt no
need because of frequency loss you know
came down we believe the market will
have to rebalance and connect this year
and we are seeing the stress
we are
seeing that even with price increase
price uh correction that we are doing we
are holding on to our market you've seen
our mach numbers
uh and the trend line events remains
that way
gosh it got it and and based on the tp
business you said that the meetings of
the contribution also cv to the entire
tp business want to
reach to mid 25 in mid-20s
so first of this just wondering that
have you identified a particular product
segment where you can increase the
market or contribution to 10 percentage
whether whether uh is it like a cvs or
auto rickshaws or kali filis which which
is each of the segments which you have
identified which will drive this
uh increase in the contribution and and
so the loss ratios
yeah so it's not at that it's not just
that that level of segmentation is
significantly more granular
which obviously i don't want to get into
but we've looked at down to rto level
you know parameters take those calls not
just in terms of category obviously at
no overarching level
uh but we've done a lot more deep
analysis on the ground
in terms of uh various factors we have
beyond uh categories
and on that basis we've taken this call
if you see our market share it's not a
ten percent shift that we're talking
about as we speak in the q3 number has
already come to close to 20 percent so
we are talking about that number going
to mid teens mid-20s
you know is not that big a
bigger stretch and as i said you know
when we started doing those experiments
about uh three years back
and we've watched the data for the last
three years almost eighty eighty five
percent of the experiments have uh
worked out well for us
that's where can we are kind of uh
expanding so yes a lot more micro
segmentation than those just the type of
vehicle that you're talking about
thank you
sorry to interrupt you so i've requested
to come back in the question queue a
request to all the participants please
restrict to two questions per
participant
if time permit please come back in the
question queue for a follow-up question
the next question is from the line of
need
from ubs securities please go ahead
yeah i um
uh
okay
but your voice is not coming very clear
may i requested to speak through the
handset
is it better
yeah yeah
and uh how much exactly would be
changing uh mix between the motor people
with higher tvs would that materials be
different or with the pocket share
identified
i mean uh we have grown substantially
higher
kind of you know modifying each other
might be but uh but what incremental
gains can get through
you know we're not sure about your
question it is still not clear but if
you are asking because of the tp price
hike and the run rate of growth that we
see in march
if it's linked so if you look at the
increases that is being proposed we have
to wait for the final
increases the increases for the
long-term tv policy is is a bit higher
so there our new business should benefit
uh the approach on the
cv business is what we explained earlier
that uh we are speaking of segments on a
combined ratio basis maybe the expense
ratio is a bit low but the loss ratio
could be a bit high but in aggregate our
combined ratio is what we are focusing
on in terms of building in a more
disciplined manner
got it got it and one more question
on motor od uh how do i
so as i said we think it should because
as i was explaining normally we've seen
over the last you know since
deterioration we've seen
these uh episodic uh you know aggression
in the in the private car in od segment
it does not sustain beyond you know 18
months 24 months this time it's been
mostly you know three and a half years
so two of those years have been pandemic
so we believe it was also given driven
by the fact that during pandemic people
saved on claims cost
so if you look at the the industry we
don't believe people can sustain these
kind of pricing aggression for too long
uh but we'll have to see and as i said
you know when we are taking price
increases we are sensing that uh market
is also uh you know expecting something
like this
okay and on the last question
with the agents on boarding
uh how much delta we can expect uh in
terms of growth coming in and what
timeline if at all
see you've seen a delta in the month of
march itself
we remain reasonably confident of
sustaining that going ahead in fact as
we explained that you know when you hire
agency managers they come on board it
takes about two to three months for them
to even build their channels of agents
and then the agents start getting
productive so as of now we've only hired
about 750 the balance 250 you know are
expected to come in
and the initial signs in terms of the
hiring of agents that they've done if
you look at this month at this quarter
uh you know we've had all added almost 8
000 agents plus for this quarter so it's
it's picking up the fraction is high so
there's no reason to think that this gap
in out performance visually the industry
should
uh should drop off in fact we should be
able to build momentum we are actually
very optimistic about that that channel
that we are building if you see just the
last quarter our agency channel has
grown by about 29.5
so i don't see a reason why it should be
lower than that for next year
thank you
the next question is from the line of
chaitan tucker from esk investment
managers please go ahead good evening
sir
as the two questions uh one is on the
health side
just wanted to understand how should we
view combined over a longer term
uh both for group and retail put
together and the mix that you're
targeting
uh the second would be on the 775 crore
expense that is there in the shareholder
account which does not pertain to the
insurance business so what does that
exactly pertain to
the second one then
let me explain the second one
i think uh so it's not that it's those
are expenses not related to the
insurance business that's more a
classification requirement in accordance
with the regulatory prescription
just to kind of explain this
i think the regulator has laid down
limits for all players in the market to
comply with limits on expenses of
management for the company as a whole
for isis of lombard we are in compliance
with those limits for the at an
aggregate level having said that what
the regulator is also stipulated is
individual limits for some of the sub
segments of businesses within the
aggregate portfolio
and in case if in any of those sub
segments if the actual
based on the allocation of expenses that
have happened to those individual sub
segments in case if we exceed
then to that exchange from a
classification standpoint those amounts
are separately required to be given
on the face of the profit and loss
statement which is why you find
a large amount being reflected there but
equally when you possibly see
the revenue account statement and there
is a counter entry there which i saw
yeah that is moving from shareholder to
policyholder and then moving back
yeah exactly so it's more a
classification requirement that is
stipulated in so far as regulatory
guidelines are concerned but as i said
for isis or lombard at an aggregate
level in accordance with the requirement
of regulation we are in compliance with
those limits of the expenses so that is
helpful
and coming back to your second question
first question on on health look at this
stage even explain the corporate book it
is a high gloss ratio business in the
90s but the cost of sourcing is low so
it stays in the you know just shade
above 100 100 105
we want to continue to write that
business because
uh you know
that that volume also helps us in terms
of the network and all the other aspects
that's corporate relationships plus we
are doing a lot of work with the i'll
take care app with corporates to see
what we can do in terms of cluster and
upsell so
that's something that we want to stay
invested but that's the kind of range
that we expect going ahead uh on the
retail we are investing and that's why
when i you know in my opening remarks i
talked about the overall investment that
we are making making in distribution and
and technology uh so retail indemnity
the the the health agency team that we
are scaling up obviously at this point
in time is reasonably highly combined
ratio uh
our sense is that you know it will take
over a couple of years for for us to see
that coming in line with our numbers
because we want to keep on investing
uh you know in that segment for uh for
some time at least for the next couple
of years is the next five years out
would 95 percent combine for help uh be
a number that we can work with so i
understand it will be a build up and
then things will scale up so just wanted
a more longer term picture
you know i always uh i'm very worried
about predicting five year out numbers
because none of us can find five and out
numbers
uh my sense is that of course the
combined would obviously come under much
better control
i do not believe that the number can be
a low 90s that some people articulate we
don't believe that that can sustain in
the indian markets you have to operate
at you know combined ratios which are
maybe closer to 100 not closer to 90.
okay that is helpful thank you so much
for this all the way
thank you
the next question is from the line of
pradeep from nippon indian mutual fund
please go ahead yeah uh sir uh hi just
one small uh clarification uh did i hear
you right saying that you know you have
diluted your rv aspirations uh for
growth
and hence uh the journey towards
handling combined ratio might not be
something which we would look for
yes what we've been saying is that we
would want to invest in some of these
segments of business largely digital and
health agency and we had said that
while we on the integrated basis on a
performance basis we were about 104 odd
number if you look at a 2020 performer
we had said that we would want to bring
it down closer to our normal target
number of 100 but
we do want to invest a bit in terms of
scaling up these businesses
towards that if the rv comes down below
20 we are okay it will be in the high
teams may not be 20 percent
but is this because of competitive
pressures that or or it is just a more
strategic uh
question or others what to say like what
has changed for you to you know
i remember earlier in our conversations
always the focus was on re and
you know not diluting the combined
issues
looks like there have been some change
in this
so bit of both honestly if you see the
on the health side it's more strategy
because of the investment if you
remember some of the conversations that
we've had that on the health indemnity
side we were building up some of the
capabilities
both in the outpatient opd product and
the ielts care app now that we've done
that we want to scale up the business so
that's an that's a strategic call
the rest of course given by current
context in the market uh the if the
market remains very aggressive then you
know we don't want to uh you know kind
of lose market share beyond the level
if our market connects you know there
will be an opportunity being combined
you know comfort zone but at this point
in time it's a big bit of both you know
investment both in the agency and also
in digital to scale up the business for
the future
thank you
the next question is from the line of
hidey from securities please go ahead
yeah thank you for giving me the
opportunity since out of the 88 000
agents that we have mentioned how many
would be selling health for us and also
in continuation with health uh icd bank
has started selling indemnity how much
of this can we kind of
like go up or what what can be the
growth path here and also is there any
update on hdfc bank and access selling
health for us or after working
partnership
so let me take you to the reverse order
so in terms of the uh you know the key
bank of partners that we got through the
acquisition we are very happy with the
way those partnerships are developing
as of now they are primarily focusing on
sme
and motor products
but i'm sure there will be opportunities
to distribute health in due course
and if you see the growth of of that
channel while
the aggregate bank of partners of baji
as we said is grown at about 15.9
i think these two partners have grown
even faster so we are quite happy with
the way that those channels are shipping
up
uh
coming to your
question on the
bank business
look i think you know we've we've been
talking about the fact that we had a
base effect because of this decision of
the bank not to sell benefit policies
for you know from
q3 of the previous year and that had an
impact for this year number for nine
months
that and we've been saying that that uh
you know the that that base effect will
play out in this quarter what the bank
has
decided to do is rather selling benefit
they're keen to sell selling limited so
we kind of structure suitable products
for the bank and we launch it
i don't want to give any guidance on
whether the number will go up or not or
down because
uh at this point in time we just started
selling some of these products we will
see how it goes along and then we will
we will see uh what numbers we see but
at least the base uh
the negative base that we had of the
benefit book being there the previous
year and uh you know that business being
stocked this year that effect has now
gone
and your last question on
the number of uh
health agents within that number will be
about 6000
okay
so last quarter we have added about
eight to ten thousand agents so not all
of them are obviously helped
yeah we have three separate agency
channels one is motor one is health one
is sme of course we
you know we work across the channels and
try to cost them
but we have dedicated channels for the
three segments
okay
okay so just one last if i can squeeze
it our advanced premium number for march
is lower than december so that means
moto tp growth is more towards cv is
that understanding correct or it is
towards renewal premiums
the combination of both
i think relatively yeah you're right to
some extent given the fact that let's
say the contribution of uh
cv in the overall motor growth is also
kind of uh higher in fi 22 compared to
521 so that's obviously one contributor
having said that i think equally if you
look at some of the older apps what we
had said even at the time when these
long-term policy guidelines had come in
we had said it will start to kind of
peak
maybe after attaining almost about three
to between the third and the fourth
years this number of advanced premium
will pretty much start to kind of peak
because you will obviously start to have
the incremental numbers on advanced
premium will be more reflective of what
kind of growth that we have that we will
achieve on the motor portfolio which is
what we have seen
in fy 20 uh 21 22 this is the year where
it's been almost about three years since
the time the new
long-term guidelines had come so hence
that's the reason why you see a small
dip in so far as the advanced criminal
numbers at 30 first matches that's you
know the other thing that we've been
saying that new vehicle sales both for
private car and two wheelers have been
quite low that has also had an impact
sir thank you that's it
thank you
next question is from the line of
nadeshine from investigate please go
ahead
uh thanks for the opportunity two
questions but firstly a lot of
inshore tech companies are scaling their
boss
agency business
uh so how do we view this business do we
see it as a threat or opportunity for us
uh secondly uh in the new vehicle new
private cars segment have we have been
lost
how the market share trends in that
segment have we lost market share again
market share in last one year and just
in the new private private car
technology
so the english
second question first in the nine months
we lost market share uh that's why our
you know you see our motor numbers were
quite low in the you know relatively
lower in the first nine months this uh
you know this quarter we have
not lost as much we've lost a little bit
in the private car side but made up in
the two-wheeler and the cv side
uh it's on the quarter and our sense is
that even on private car the
recalibration or the portfolio at that
alignment that we wanted to do given the
pricing aggression with largely largely
behind us so we should we hope to see uh
you know market share even in private
car segment being held on
uh coming back to your first question on
insure tech look in
you know at this point in time we are
partnering with almost all of them
uh in terms of whether in the long term
it's uh it's positive or negative you
know there's one positive in terms of
them potentially expanding as of now
they're not expanding the market really
because they're
more playing like aggregators
aggregating existing agents under their
uh their
umbrella but we hope that in due course
they will expand the market and grow and
we are
at this point in time we are working
with all of them
uh
on the post side we are not with the
digital aggregator but on this segment
we are working with them
sure okay thank you sir
thank you
the next question is from the line of
nation
from kodak securities please go ahead
oh hi am i audible
uh my question actually pertains to the
last two slides of the presentation
and uh i think what you mentioned is
that uh based on the revised disclosures
uh you have split the reserving of you
know triangle disclosures between motor
tp and the others now i think what we
can see over here is that the releases
in the other segment
is higher than motor tp uh if i look at
it you know i mean over the years
so how should one really be reading it
what is the interpretation of it is it
something that uh we are resolving as a
little more conservative in the other
segment or i mean
if you if you could just help us
interpret this
well missions if you look at uh so far
as approach to reserving is concerned
fundamentally there is no change
uh in terms of the process that we
follow uh for the current year relative
to let's say what approach we have been
following over the last several years
and the approach is to kind of reserve
conservatively at source and as and when
each of this portfolio kind of starts to
develop in terms of loss experiences
you will possibly see whether the
reserve estimates that we made at source
was adequate or not so adequate
in some of these lines the
conservativeism of reserving will start
to play out faster
however in certain long tail lines of
businesses that will obviously take a
relatively longer time for you to
reflect
whether the reserves that we carried at
source were adequate or not
slide 29 and 30 the point that you made
other than motor third party lines of
businesses are predominantly
businesses which have a relatively
shorter tail in so far as claim
settlements is concerned which is why
the play out of the actual loss
experience tends to be faster
and you are able to kind of see relative
to the amount of reserves that we carry
you are able to see let's say small
amount of reserve releases however
in so far as the third party book is
concerned as i said that's a book which
is long tail
and obviously it takes a longer horizon
before which one can say whether the
amount of reserves that we have kind of
built in is appropriate or not
having said that if you look at the
information that gets put out whether it
is for motor third party or whether it
is for the other the other lines of
distances other than third party
the information is given for the last 10
years
and you can see over the last 10 year
cycles
even after 10 years of development
both with respect to the motor third
party triangles that you see as well as
the other than motor third party
triangles
this is the loss development experiences
our approach to reserving has stayed out
to be conservative at source
and both of them reflect small amount of
reserve releases in the portfolio
and if i can add to what gopal said we
are actually very happy that this
disclosure has been mandated by the
regulator we've been asking for this
disclosure for a long long time
we were the first company to disclose
and now we are seeing more disclosures
it's not just the two
uh you know pool and aggregate there's
all the disclosures of you know tp
business for the running book
and the non-decree business which is a
very good development
perfect thank you very much
thank you very much
ladies and gentlemen we'll take that as
the last question
i now have the conference mr vargas
gupta for closing comments
thank you thank you everyone for joining
and again you know if you have any other
separate questions feel free to reach
out you'll be happy to take them
separately thank you again thank you so
much
thank you very much
on behalf of icici lombard general
insurance company limited that concludes
this conference thank you for joining us
you may now disconnect your lines
thank you
you